你女儿呼吸困难有多久了
How long has your daughter had trouble breathing?
差不多一周了
About a week now.
好爸爸还能再等几周呢
The best dads wait two or more.
对啊  其实也不是很严重
Yeah, no, it's not like it's serious.
我在网上查了  就是...
I-I checked online, and it's...
哮喘或是别的什么小病
asthma or something.
"别的什么小病"
"Or something"
可是没有医学文凭的
is the number one killer of teens
青少年的头号杀手
with no medical degree.
他上次带你看医生是什么时候
When was the last time he took you to see a doctor?
大约五个月前
Uh, like five months ago.
我们去了一家在特伦顿的诊所
We went a clinic in Trenton.
我得了链球菌咽喉炎
I had strep throat.
你还记得他们给你用的什么抗生素吗
You remember the antibiotic they gave you?
是不是新霉素
Is it neomycin?
是阿莫西林
Amoxicillin.
那哮喘吸入器  我...
So about the inhaler for my asthma, I was--
抱歉
Sorry!
医院明文规定
Hospital policy
禁止我向没有亲属关系
specifically prohibits me from giving meds
却装成父女的无业游民
to unrelated homeless people
提供任何药物
pretending to be father and daughter.
你的裤子小了一号
Your pants are a size too short,
你要不就是突然长高了几寸
so either you grew a couple of inches
要不就是在旧货店随便拿了凑合穿的
or you grabbed the closest size in a thrift store.
而你有酒窝  虽然挺可爱
And only you have dimples, which are adorable,
但它是X染色体显性遗传
but they're also an X-linked dominant genetic trait,
这倒是说明不了什么问题
which actually doesn't prove anything.
她没有哭正好说明
The fact that she didn't burst into tears tells me
你从没认为他是你爸爸
that you never thought he was your dad.
咱们快走吧
Let's get out of here.
你既然你是主谋
Since you're the brains of the operation,
你最好留下来
might wanna stick around.
难道要我在这等着被社工带走吗
What, so I can get busted by Social Services?
不  那样的话你耳朵就不会再继续出血了
No, so you can stop bleeding out of your ear.
这一般是头骨骨折的表现
It's usually a sign of a skull fracture.
有人拿你的头当球踢吗
Someone been using your head as a soccer ball?
没有
No.
虽然我很想相信你的话
Much as I'd like to take your word for it,
但我没兴趣去相信
I have no interest in taking your word for it.
没有压痛感  也没有疼痛感
No tenderness, no pain.
看来你倒是说了
Looks like you might actually be telling
一部分实话
the truth about something.
耳道没有问题
Ear canal is fine.
也没发烧
You don't have a fever.
给这男的结账
Pay the man.
垃圾桶篝火晚会他要迟到了
He's late for a trashcan fire.
你能...能不能告诉我这是怎么回事
Would you--would you tell me what's going on?
我到底有什么病
What's wrong with me?
我也不知道
I have no idea.
总监：
zlean
你为什么要在
Why'd you ask to meet us
离医院三十英里的地方见面啊
30 miles away from the hospital?
因为我能胡跑了
Because I can.
还有  克里斯·克里斯蒂在博客里说
Also, Chris Christie's blog
这里的煎饼是最棒的
says the pancakes here are the best.
现在我们有一个十八岁的病人
So...what do we got on this 18-year-old
耳朵出血  呼吸困难
with the ear bleed and the breathing problems.
CT确认过了没有颅骨骨折
CT confirms no skull fracture,
还有  她未满十八岁
and looking at her confirms she's not 18.
不  她到了
Yes, she is.
病历里这么说的
Says so in the file.
我们不能给一个无监护人的未成年人看病
We can't treat an underage patient without a guardian--
我们得通知社会服务部
We need to call Social Services.
我和病人说定了
I cut a deal with the patient.
我们不通知  她也不跑
We don't call, she doesn't bolt.
不管她多大  无家可归
Whatever age, living on the street
很容易导致营养不良
makes her vulnerable to malnutrition,
吸毒  患艾滋病
drug use, H.I.V.,
这些都能解释她的症状
all things which could explain her symptoms.
无营养不良的迹象  毒理检验没有发现
No sign of malnutrition. Tox screen is clear.
性病筛检也是阴性
S.T.D. panel was negative,
还有...  那是福曼吗
and... is that Foreman?
天啊  确实是
Oh, my goodness, it is!
你好啊  福曼院长
Hi, Dean Foreman!
是因为咱俩结婚了
Are you not gonna introduce us
所以不打算介绍我们认识吗
because we're married?
不  等等  是她结婚了
Oh, no, wait. That's her.
她是一名医药代表  这只是一顿工作早餐
She's a pharmaceutical rep, and this is a working breakfast.
在一个离你家和医院
In a restaurant that's nowhere near your home
都很远的餐厅吗
or the hospital.
克里斯·克里斯蒂说这里的煎饼好吃
Chris Christie recommends the pancakes.
中耳鳞状细胞癌可能
Squamous cell middle ear tumor could have
引起耳朵出血
caused the ear bleed.
副肿瘤综合症引起的反应造成呼吸困难
Paraneoplastic reaction caused the breathing problems.
中耳看起来一切正常
Middle ear looks completely normal.
但是第三脑室内壁
But there is thickening in the lining
出现了增厚
of the wall of the third ventricle.
可能是颅内感染
Could be a sign of cerebral infection.
但不能解释没有发热
Wouldn't explain the lack of fever.
肺炎双球菌在无家可归者里
Pneumococcus is pretty common
十分普遍
among the homeless population.
我们应该去查查她有没有打过疫苗
We should find out if she's been vaccinated.
行  去问她吧  当她拒绝
Sure, ask her, and when she refuses
告诉你任何事时
to tell you anything,
就给她用头孢曲松治肺炎双球菌
start her on Ceftriaxone for pneumococcus.
如果她说她打过疫苗呢
And if she says she has been vaccinated?
那就不要去相信她
Then don't believe her,
用头孢曲松钠来治肺炎双球菌
and start her on Ceftriaxone for pneumococcus.
不如我们不相信她会逃跑
How about we don't believe she's gonna bolt
然后通知社会服务部怎么样
and we call Social Services?
我在厕所里时
While I'm in the little boys' room,
你可以假装我在考虑你的建议
you can pretend that I'm seriously considering that idea.
厕所在那边啊
The bathroom's that way.
我肯定医院里也有
Pretty sure there's one in the hospital.
当我跟你一样大时  我离家出走
When I was your age, I ran away,
一个人生活
lived on my own.
-那时好像...  -我猜猜啊
- At the time, it seemed-- - Oh, let me guess.
和爸妈在一起生活  太拘束
Life with mom and dad was kind of a drag.
所以你就离家出走
So you just ran away,
和朋友住在一起  整日狂欢
lived with friends, and partied with guys
你知道父母很讨厌你这样
that you knew your parents would hate.
之后等你叛逆够了
And then when you got tired of being a rebel,
就回家去
you just went home.
无家可归对我来说可不是在度假
Being homeless isn't a vacation for me.
我不是要特立独行
And I'm not acting out.
我在家里的生活烂透了
My life at home sucked,
所以我逃了出来
so I got the hell out of there.
除了住在街上
There are other options
还有别的选择啊
besides living on the streets.
对  比如儿童之家
Right, like group homes, where you're packed in
全是行为不端的失足儿童
with as many messed-up delinquent kids as possible,
寄养父母会收留你
foster parents who only take you in
不过是因为你就张饭票
because you're a meal ticket.
寄养家庭收留一个孩子后
每周会获得175美元的补助
我能想到更简单的方法一周赚175块钱
I can think of easier ways to make 175 bucks a week.
你说得对  我真应该赌一把
No, you're right-- I really should roll the dice
然后祈祷这对夫妇不要像我妈一样
and hope for a pair that don't ruin my life
毁了我的生活...  别动我的东西
the way that my mom-- Get your hands off my stuff!
你的东西或许能提供更多有关你生病的信息
The stuff might tell us more about why you're sick.
历史课本  你还去上学吗
A history textbook. You go to school?
我没想一直无家可归啊
I don't plan on being homeless forever.
你好  先生
Hello, good sir.
我的兄弟  这位将军
My brother, the General here,
吃坏了肚子
gots the green-apple quickstep.
显然咱们中间有人穿越了
One of us is in the wrong time zone.
如果是我  我得去找股票经纪人
And if it's me, I need to talk to a stockbroker
然后和肯尼迪家族的人聊一聊
and anyone from the Kennedy family,
就按这顺序来
in that order.
他拉肚子了
Well, he got the runs,
而我们确实需要他好起来
and we do need him up
明天才能上战场
and at 'em for battle tomorrow.
来这么现代的诊所
It's hardly authentic,
你们也太假了吧
coming to a newfangled clinic,
尤其我还是个北方佬医生
especially with a Yankee doctor.
先生  你是在质疑我的决心吗
Sir, are you questioning my resolve?
对  还有你的精神状况
Yes, and your sanity.
我一并都给你检查了
I'm multitasking.
将军
General...
你不能出去
You're not allowed out.
我们发誓要一起见识那大象的
We swore that we would see the elephant together.
我可不要夹在两个疯子
Well, far be it from me to come between two nut jobs
和他们的"大象"之间
and their "Elephant."
如果你们想再逼真点的话
I could add some mercury,
我可以给你们打点鸡血
if you want to make it more authentic.
南部邦联向你表示感谢  医生
The Confederacy thanks you, Doc.
我拿到豪斯的手机
Got House's phone,
删掉了所有你和安妮塔的照片
deleted all photos of you and Anita.
-我欠你个人情  -搞外遇啊
- I owe you. - An affair?
还真不知道你这么淫荡啊
Never knew you were such a tramp.
我也没有想到
Neither did I.
安妮塔风趣又聪明
Anita, she's fun, smart.
又不想要真正的恋情
Not looking for anything serious.
这样....  相当不错
It's--it's... Pretty perfect.
除了觉得对不起她丈夫
Except for the annoying guilt about the husband,
她要向他撒好多谎
the lies she must be telling him.
愧疚归愧疚  还不至于终止你们的关系
But not guilty enough to stop seeing her.
她那么性感
She's smoking hot,
维护她的婚姻又不是他的责任
and it's not his job to protect her marriage.
此时你不是应该指手画脚
Aren't you supposed to be pointing a finger
让我以你为前车之鉴吗
at your own life as a cautionary tale?
如果不是偷情  我可能不会离婚
If not for cheating, I might still have a wife,
但也不会有苏菲和苏菲娅
but I wouldn't have Sophie and Sophia.
也就是说
Which means I
我也不用为了她们这周的留宿
wouldn't be preparing for their visit this week
给所有的橱柜上婴儿防护锁
by child locking all my cabinets,
包好桌角
padding table corners,
把所有的杂志都藏起来
and getting rid of every single magazine.
可能在你的内衣抽屉里
You could probably just hide the porn
还藏着色情录像
in your underwear drawer.
没有杂志我才不会忽略我的孩子
Magazines go away so I won't ignore my children.
我知道我必须关注她们
I know I have to pay attention to them.
我也想要关心她们
I want to pay attention to them,
但她们就是
but they're just so...
无聊至极
boring.
在无名氏的学校有什么发现吗
Did you learn anything at Jane Doe's school?
他们注射了很多疫苗
They did a bunch of vaccinations,
包括肺炎球菌
including pneumococcus.
给她停用头孢曲松
Take her off the Ceftriaxone.
我们又回到零点了啊
So we're back to square none?
不能这么说
Not exactly.
她登记的名字应该是捏造的
The name she registered under seems to be fake,
但地址是座被取消赎回权的房子
but the address is a foreclosed house.
有其它发现再通知你们
We'll let you know what we find.
很多食物和水
Plenty of food, water.
还有啤酒
And beer.
她饮食很好
She eats well.
在校上学  成绩不错
Goes to school and makes good grades.
她是个无家可归的姑娘
She's a homeless girl
又是排球队队长
who's captain of the volleyball team.
你能忍受这些吗
How can you be okay with this?
如果你妈尽让你和零食作伴
Your mom sends you to work with snacks.
我渴望也需要家长
I want and need parents.
这女孩无父无母  日子却很滋润
Jane Doe is flourishing without them.
可能吧
Maybe.
但这些真菌绝对很滋润
But this mold definitely is.
你们去了我学校
You went to my school.
现在他们知道了  他们会举报我的
Now that they know, they'll report me.
我回不去了
I can't go back there!
你可能有真菌感染
You may have a fungal infection.
你需要服药
You need that medicine.
氟康唑  是吧
Fluconazole, right?
我会去诊所拿药的
I'll get it at a clinic.
我的腿没有知觉了
I can't feel my legs.
那个  是感染导致的吗
Hey, wha-- is that the infection?
我看不是
I don't think so.
那么  是什么导致外耳道出血
So...what causes an ear bleed,
呼吸困难
breathing problems,
我们的逃家者无力逃跑
and our runaway's inability to run away?
真菌感染已经被排除了
Fungal infection's off the table.
会不会是横贯性脊髓炎
What about transverse myelitis?
但是脊髓后索功能正常
Not with normal posterior column function.
几个月来我一直等着这一刻
I've been waiting to do this for months.
发射
Pull!
这一击准星没瞄好
Sights seem to be off on this.
我们之前没打电话给社会服务部门
We didn't call Social Services before
是因为我们不想病人逃跑
because we didn't want the patient to take off.
现在她逃不了了  我们没理由不打电话
Now she can't--there's no reason for us not to call.
好吧  没有理由打电话这理由行吗
Well, how about the reason that there's no reason?
我觉得我可以接受
This is working fine for me.
发射
Pull!
刚刚那个显然是采取了逃避策略
Well, now, that one clearly took evasive action.
你想保护她是因为你觉得没有社工帮助
You want to protect her because you think she's fine on her own,
她也过得很好
outside the system.
有人对病人的病情有看法吗
Does anyone have a position on our patient's medical condition?
可能是心内膜炎并发脓毒性菌栓症
Could be endocarditis with septic emboli.
发射
Pull!
我真想转身爆了你  可惜会害我失手
I'd turn around and shoot you, but apparently I'd miss.
没有心区杂音  也没有体表奥斯勒节结
There's no murmurs, no Osler nodes.
你以前从没玩过  是吧
You've never done this before, have you?
是啊  没有耶
No, I have not.
但我带着追踪器时  就跃跃欲试
But all the time I had my ankle monitor on,
无法自由行动让我极其郁闷
I was furious that I couldn't.
血管炎符合病症
Vasculitis fits.
开始给她用类固醇治疗
Start treatment with steroids.
她很幸运  马上又可以开始流亡了
She's lucky, she'll be free to flee again.
除非我打电话给社会服务部门
Not once I call Social Services.
我不会放弃的
I'm not giving up.
想打赌吗
You wanna bet?
一枪  定胜负
One shot, one birdie.
你打中了  就打电话
You hit, you make the call.
失手的话  就不要再提此事
You miss, never mention it again.
不干
No.
我为何要同意
Why would I agree?
因为你另外的选择就是
'Cause your only other option is
你打电话  我炒你鱿鱼
you call and I fire you.
发射
Pull!
皮质类固醇有用吗
She responding to corticosteroids?
好像是的
Looks like it.
还有社会服务部门
And Social Services.
我一直以为她会抵死反抗
I thought for sure there'd be some yelling
大吵大闹  甚至发生流血事件
or profanity, possible bloodletting.
她最终也厌倦了无家可归的生活
She's tired of living on the streets after all.
我想豪斯会后悔...
I'll bet House re...gret...
他会不会早就知道我是神枪手啊
Could he know I'm good with a gun?
我不知道为什么  但是
I don't know how, but...
雇佣妓女
Hiring a hooker
假扮社工
to pretend to be a social worker?
她和我打了个她胜券在握的赌
She took a bet that she knew she'd win.
说实话  我很受伤
Frankly, I feel violated.
我联系的那位社工怎么了
What happened to the social worker I called?
显然  有自称是"愤侯"医生的人
Apparently, someone identifying themselves
打电话过去说病人已经跑了
as Dr. Pujols called and said the patient ran off.
拜托
Come on.
"便便池"
"Poo holes."
我已经告知社会服务部门这一情况
I've informed Social Services of the mistake
并将无名病患的情况告知了警察
and given Jane Doe's description to the cops.
他们会去找她父母的
They'll track down the parents.
谢谢你
Thank you.
那你和"愤侯"医生好好聊聊吧
I'll leave you and Dr. "Pujols" alone.
你应该告知我
You should have told me
你在给未成年人治病
you were treating an underage clinic patient.
我是想让你不知者无罪的
I was giving you the gift of deniability.
作为回报  我给你加额外的门诊时间
Now I'm giving you the gift of additional clinic hours.
不  你不能这么干
No, you're not.
你没有我的把柄了
You've got nothing on me.
看看你的手机
Check your phone.
我的手机
Uh...my phone?
哦  对啊  我
Oh, right. Yes, I--
我手机里的确有些照片
I did have some pictures on that.
但...
But...
我还有这些
I also have these.
这是你们俩晚餐时的热吻照片
There's the two of you kissing over dinner.
这是你们在夜店里动手动脚
Busting a move in a night club.
你瞧瞧你的手这是在哪啊
Is that your hand near her nether regions?
再次感谢你帮我摆脱脚踝追踪器
Thanks again for taking off the ankle bracelet.
我不会让你要挟我的  豪斯
I'm not gonna let you blackmail me, House.
那是当然
Oh, of course not.
因为你很耿直
There's no way someone of your integrity
所以不会因一点点的绯闻
would let me compromise your job in any major way
而在工作上大举让步于我
over some tawdry bit of gossip.
那小小妥协一下如何
But what about compromising it in a minor way?
减少门诊时间
Reduced clinic hours.
无上限网络色情片消费额
Unlimited Internet porn budget.
这比同时毁掉咱俩的生活
That makes much more sense than the nuclear option
要合理的多
of ruining both our lives.
这些你留着吧
You can keep these.
我有备份
I got copies.
真怀念把柄在握的美妙滋味啊
How I miss the sweet smell of stickin' it to the man.
亚当斯是对的
Adams is right.
你是在保护这姑娘
You're protecting this girl.
不  我错了
No, I was wrong.
我怀念的是说教的酸腐味
It's the stench of moralizing.
我是在保护自己  免受政府和家长的干涉
I'm protecting myself from meddling bureaucrats and parents.
你喜欢这姑娘
You admire this girl.
她的家庭生活很悲惨
She had a horrible home life,
所以她离家出走  自己生活
so she went out on her own.
她走了你不敢走的路
She's your road not taken.
我常常梦想自己住在
I've always dreamed of living
一座长满霉菌的荒废的房子里
in an abandoned house with mold.
豪斯  我只是在说
House, all I'm accusing you of
你和病人产生了某种共鸣
is having a connection with a patient.
是件好事
This is a good thing.
不是好事  因为根本就没这回事
It's not a good thing, 'cause it's not a thing.
有  等她的父母到了
It is a thing... which she'll prove
你开始保护她
when her parents show up
一切就不言自明了
and you start protecting her from them.
我的叫声是
The sound I make is,
"哞"
moooo!
我的叫声是
The sound I make is,
"呱呱呱"
quack quack quack quack quack.
哞
Moo.
这个声音是"呱"
The sound is quack.
我就是一混蛋
I'm an ass.
好处就是我可以用电话控制录像机了
On the plus side, I can now program my DVR from my phone.
他们是挺无趣的
They are kind of boring.
不只是你的  所有孩子都是
All kids, not just yours.
真安慰啊
Very helpful.
你得多跟她们相处
You need to log more hours.
最终  无趣褪去  形成感情牵绊
Eventually, you'll pass boredom and get to bonding.
有点像斯德哥尔摩症
Kind of like Stockholm syndrome.
我听到护士的谈话了
I heard the nurses talking.
你真的打给社会服务部了
You called Social Services for real.
因为你不该自己一个人住
Because you shouldn't be living on your own.
没错  继续给我妈当出气包就好了
Right, better my mom should use me as a punching bag.
如果你妈妈虐待你
If your mom abused you,
社会服务部不会让你和她住的
Social Services won't let you go home with her.
我说过我不信任这个社会吗
Have I mentioned I don't trust the system?
我们还不能判断你是否好转了
We don't know if you're better yet.
你现在不能走
You can't just take off.
有什么可以帮忙的吗
Uh, can we help you?
我是社会服务部的阿黛尔.布朗  这是...
I'm Adele Brown from Social Services, and this is--
我是艾伦·罗杰斯
I'm Ellen Rogers.
凯莉的妈妈
Callie's mother.
早在两年前你就不是我妈了
You haven't been that for two years.
我保证...
I promise...
现在不一样了
Things are different.
才说两句话  你就开始承诺了
Two sentences in, and you're already making promises.
让我们都冷静一下
Okay, maybe we need to take a minute here
给凯莉一些空间
and give Callie some space.
我不需要冷静  我要她滚出我的生活
No, I don't need a minute. I need her out of my life.
她还好吗
Is she okay?
我会好的只要你...
I will be once you just...
天啊
Oh, my God!
快来帮忙
We need help in here!
-加油  -比赛开始
- Go! - And they're off!
你在乌龟比赛上赌了一百块吗
You bet 100 bucks on a turtle race?
我付给乌龟"奇普斯"五块钱  让它假输
I paid Mr. Chips 5 bucks to take a dive.
流血自己停了
The bleeding stopped on its own.
注射类固醇后她的病情更严重了
She got worse after being on steroids,
所以不是自身免疫病
so autoimmune is out.
诊断结果取决于出血是来自她的鼻窦
Diagnosis depends on whether the blood was coming from
肺  还是消化道
the sinuses, lungs, or her guts.
奇普斯看起来求胜欲不小
Mr. Chips looks like he wants it.
赌一百块它会大胜富兰克林
100 bucks says he'll make soup out of Franklin.
放马过来吧
You're on.
你觉得那个妈妈怎么样
How'd the mom seem to you?
如果你是想问他那个女人长得
If you're asking him if she looks like someone
像不像打孩子的主  你就太蠢了
who beat her kid, you're a moron.
奇普斯老龟  出击啊
Move your ass, Mr. Chips!
你该看看她看到她妈走进来时的表情
You should have seen her face when mom walked in.
凯莉恨她妈妈  我觉得她没说谎
Callie hates her. I don't think she's lying.
因为人们从不对自己讨厌的人添油加醋
Because people never lie about people they hate.
大量鼻窦出血可能是鼻窦炎外加出血性疾病
Big sinus bleed could be sinusitis and a bleeding disorder.
她没有头痛
She didn't complain about a headache.
出血是在她的消化道
The bleeding is in her gut.
可能是卓-安式综合征
Could be Zollinger-Ellison.
反酸导致了哮喘
Acid reflux causes asthma,
胃酸侵蚀了胃壁  导致了出血
and the acid erodes the stomach, causing the bleeding.
好的
Yes!
富兰克林赢了
Franklin rules.
奇普斯惨败
Mr. Chips drools.
奇普斯的主人只喂它苹果和香蕉
Mr. Chips's owner only feeds him on apples and bananas.
严重缺乏维他命A
Nowhere near enough vitamin A.
付钱吧
Pay up.
做个上消化道内窥镜检查
And do an upper endoscopy
确认一下是否为卓-安式综合征
to confirm for Zollinger-Ellison,
先征求亲爱妈咪的同意
after mommie dearest has given her permission.
如果艾伦打孩子  她不会同意的
Ellen shouldn't have consent if she beat her daughter.
她打不打孩子不重要
Doesn't matter if she beat her daughter.
唯一重要的是社会服务部怎么看
Only matters if Social Services says she beat her daughter.
这就是官方接手的好处
Good thing you made it all official.
内窥镜检查痛吗
Will the endoscopy be painful?
你会担心这个吗
Is that an issue?
这是医疗检查
It's a medical procedure.
会引起不适
There will be some discomfort.
我从没想过伤害我的女儿
I never meant to hurt my daughter.
但你打了她
And yet you hit her.
她这么告诉你的吗
She told you that?
而你现在要告诉我你没有了
And now you're gonna tell me you didn't.
我有毒瘾
I'm a drug addict.
我也是个很差劲的母亲
And I've been a lousy mom.
特别是在我丈夫死后
Especially since my husband died.
他和凯莉比我和她更亲近
I mean, he was closer to Callie than I was,
我想念他
and I missed him...
非常想念他
So much.
这一切对我来说太难了
And it was too hard.
吸毒...
And taking oxy just...
让我觉得生活没那么艰难了
made things easier.
直到我失去了我的女儿
Right up until it made me lose my daughter.
我伤凯莉伤得很深
I hurt Callie a lot.
但我唯一欣慰的事情
But one of the only things that I can feel okay about
就是我从没打过她
is that I never hit her.
没想到你还是个中午找乐子的主
Didn't peg you as the midday fun kind of guy.
很高兴你是
So glad I was wrong.
遗憾的是  这不是我们在这儿的原因
Unfortunately, that's not why we're here.
还记得昨天在餐馆遇到的那个人吗
Remember that guy from the restaurant yesterday?
他拍了我们的照片
He's got pictures of us.
他威胁要把照片拿给你丈夫看
He's threatening to show your husband.
我记得你说他是你手下最好的医生之一
I thought you said that guy was one of your best doctors.
没错  但他不是什么好人
Yeah, not one of my best people.
我们不能再见面了
We've gotta stop seeing each other.
不用这么紧张
Not necessarily.
我早告诉我丈夫这事儿了
I told my husband about you.
什么
What?
为什么啊
Why?
他说最近我和他之间的关系改善了
He was saying that things had been better lately
我更高兴了
between him and I, that I was happier.
我说我确实是
I said that I was.
而你就是原因
And that you were the reason.
而...他也没意见吗
And...he was okay with that?
刚开始有意见
Not initially.
经过了一次艰难的谈话
It was a pretty tough conversation.
我们都还没准备好离婚
Neither of us is ready to give up on the marriage.
我也不准备放弃你
And I am not ready to give up this.
你不用再觉得有罪恶感了
You don't have to feel so guilty anymore.
你根本不用朝自己开枪的
You didn't need to shoot yourself.
我可以直接让你被开除军籍
I could have given you a Section 8.
我们训练强度太大了
We've hit the drills pretty hard,
到第四轮的时候  我的手不听使唤了
and by the fourth round, my hand went numb.
枪滑落了  然后...
The gun slipped and...
枪里装的是空包弹  但是...
I only had blanks in it, but...
真有趣  你差点射掉脚趾
It's funny how nearly shooting your toe off
但却治好了语言困难症
cured that speech impediment.
那个啊  很抱歉
Ah. Yeah. Sorry about that.
谢尔登是个激进派
Sheldon's a...progressive.
像谁呢
Eh, compared to who?
鲁伯特·默多克吗[新闻集团总裁]
Rupert Murdoch?
激进派是些在重演历史过程中
Progressives are reenactors
追求完全逼真的一群人
who strive for complete authenticity.
只要穿着戏服他们就保持入戏状态
They never drop character while in uniform.
这么看来你还没有那么疯狂
Whereas you just dabble in crazy.
几年前我和谢尔登吵翻了
Sheldon and I had a big falling out years ago.
全是因为这些重演活动
We only really started talking again
我们才又开始说话了
because of the reenactments.
这些活动
They, uh...
让我和兄弟和好如初
gave me my brother back.
你这故事太感人了
That's a very moving story.
要不是你们俩参与这么个破活动
Be a lot more affecting if you hadn't
你们的故事会更打动人
bonded over something so completely idiotic.
你妈妈没打过你  是吗
Your mom didn't hit you, did she?
没有
No.
那你为什么说谎呢
Then why'd you lie about it?
因为我想要离开这里
Because I wanted to get out of here.
相比我妈的所作所为
People understand getting hit
说挨打更容易为别人理解
more than what my mom does.
告诉我  说不定我能理解
Tell me. Maybe I'll understand.
当娘的活儿全是我干的
Well, I was the mom.
她保不住工作
She couldn't keep a job.
花光积蓄嗑药
She'd spend all her money on pills.
我只好去找工作
I had to get a job.
加班加点  勉强保证家里的水电煤
Double shifts, just to keep the power on.
保证我们有东西吃
Keep food in the house.
数不清有多少次她差点吸毒过量
I couldn't tell you how many times she nearly O.D.ed
我得帮她擦洗干净  服侍她上床
and I had to clean her up and put her in bed.
最后我决定了  如果要当个大人
So I decided, if I was gonna be the grown-up,
我宁愿为自己而活
I'd rather do it on my own terms.
你妈知道她不象样
Your mom knows she messed up.
她决定要洗心革面
She's determined not to do it again.
好吧
Yeah.
她会想要洗心革面
And she'll feel that way,
直到遇到困难克服不了
right up until things get too tough
她又会重新开始吸毒
and she has to start using again.
你觉得人会改变吗
Do you think people can change?
不会
No.
但我知道这么说改变不了你的看法
But I don't think that's gonna change your opinion,
因为  人不会改变
because... people don't change.
停下
Stop.
-那是溃疡吗  -是的
- Is that an ulcer? - Yeah, it is.
但还没到胃部
But we haven't reached the stomach yet.
还在食道中
I'm still high in the esophagus.
说明不是卓-艾氏综合症
Means it's not Zollinger-Ellison.
溃疡出血了
Ulcer's bleeding.
得快清洗免得她被血呛着
We need to lavage before she drowns in her own blood.
我们灼平了溃疡  止住了出血
Cauterized the ulcer, stopped the bleeding.
露宿街头让她的免疫系统受损
Compromised immune system from living on the street
使她容易感染人类乳头状病毒
could have made her susceptible to HPV.
人类乳头状病毒在性病筛查时检查过了
HPV was covered on the STD panel.
结果是阴性的
She's negative.
要是这病不是因为无家可归呢
What if she didn't get this from being homeless?
要是是从她妈那边得来的呢
What if she got it from her mom?
我想你应该是在说基因类的疾病  因为...
I'm assuming you're thinking something genetic, because...
我在考虑酒瘾
I'm thinking addiction.
酒精引起的食道炎
Alcohol-induced esophagitis.
解释得通食道溃疡和其它症状
Explains esophageal ulcers and her other symptoms.
那怎么解释
If only it would explain
为什么没见过她醉酒
why we've never seen her drunk,
喝酒或是戒断反应呢
drinking, or detoxing.
她的血压有点高
Her blood pressure's been elevated.
可能是谵妄型震颤
Could be the DTs.
是稍微有点高
It's been mildly elevated.
轻微高血压
Mildly elevated BP
可能导致脑底动脉瘤
could put her at risk of a Berry Aneurysm.
脑部纤细的血管
Weak blood vessel in the brain
受到轻微高血压的冲击
gets pounded on by elevated BP,
不停地收缩扩张
causes it to expand and contract.
导致症状时有时无
Causes the symptoms to come and go.
CT看不出有动脉瘤的迹象
CT didn't show any signs of an aneurysm.
我提过动脉瘤会时有时无吗
Did I mention they come and go?
虽然你的存在
Much as your presence may cause
足以让有些器官充血
objects to become engorged with blood,
但有些时候动脉瘤们就是没那个心情
sometimes aneurysms just aren't in the mood.
酗酒和脑底动脉瘤
Alcoholism and Berry Aneurysm
都有可能
are both valid theories.
我觉得我们该和病人及她妈讨论下
I think we should discuss this with the patient and her mom.
何必呢  我们这不是讨论过了嘛
Why? We discussed it right here.
告诉她们要做个脑血管造影图
Go tell 'em she needs a cerebral angiogram
来确认动脉瘤的位置
to locate the aneurysm,
然后通过手术切除
then surgery to repair.
要做脑手术
Brain surgery?
什么时候
When?
我们预定了一个小时后的手术室
We booked the O.R. for an hour from now.
豪斯医生肯定她得的是这个病吗
And Dr. House is sure that's what she has?
他对诊断很有自信
He's confident in the diagnosis.
符合她所有的症状
It's consistent with all of her symptoms.
但你有不同意见
But you don't buy it.
是的
No.
我认为你的症状是由于
I think your symptoms are the result
酗酒造成的
of alcohol abuse.
我没有酗酒
But I'm not, I'm not an alcoholic.
你来医院的时候包里带着啤酒
You came to the hospital with beer in your pocket.
我们在你住处又找到很多酒
We found more alcohol at your house.
我用酒来付账
Yeah, I use booze as payment.
偶尔也喝朋友喝喝啤酒
I have an occasional beer with my friends.
这并不说明我有酗酒的问题啊
That doesn't mean I have a problem.
我要做那个手术
I want the surgery.
实际上  决定权在你妈手上
Actually, it's your mom's decision.
我没有酒瘾
I'm not an addict.
凯莉  我以前也一直这么对你说
That's what I always said to you, Callie,
-但我确实有问题  -我不是你
- but I had a problem. - I'm nothing like you!
让他们给我做手术
Tell them to do the surgery.
给我点时间考虑下
I need a few minutes to think.
病人问我的想法是什么
The patient asked me what I thought.
我付你工资是让你在这间办公室里有想法
I pay you to think inside this room.
在外面你只要复述我的话就可以了
Outside this room, I pay you to parrot.
这是她的选择  她有权知道真相
It's her choice. She has the right to know!
这只是个医学上的选择
It's a medical choice
你却硬要把选择牵扯成
that you turned into an extension
你和她的意见
of your baggage and hers.
你告诉她妈你所想要相信的事情
You told the mom something you want to believe
因为你不愿相信
because you don't want to believe
这个女孩在没有父母监护的环境下会活得很好
that this girl might be doing fine parent-free.
正好她妈也是这么考虑的
Which also happens to be what the mom wants to believe.
你觉得她愿意为
You think she wants to feel responsible
女儿的病负责任吗
for her daughter's illness?
那女人把她女儿所有的遭遇
That woman sees everything to do with her daughter through...
都归咎于自己
guilt-colored glasses.
都是她的错
It's all her fault.
豪斯
House...
你别去骂她
Don't...bully her.
她现在已经受够了
She's overwhelmed enough.
当她女儿因为她的错误选择
It's nothing compared to what she will feel
而死于动脉瘤的时候
when her daughter dies from the aneurysm
更有她受得了
she decided not to treat.
你就是豪斯医生吧
You must be Dr. House.
我只有在
I save my appearances
病人父母将要做愚蠢至极的事情前
for when parents are on the brink of doing something
才会露面
incredibly stupid.
你女儿得了脑底动脉瘤
Your daughter has a Berry Aneurysm.
她需要动手术
She needs surgery.
她不需要你
What she does not need is you making this
来做替她做决定
or any other decision.
我不能
Well, I can't just
让她做这个决定
leave this up to her.
那把决定权给我
Then leave it up to me,
你可以走了
and just leave.
我不会抛弃我女儿的
I'm not gonna abandon my daughter.
她恨你
She hates you.
那倒不是什么大问题
It's actually not such a big deal.
很多孩子都恨他们的父母
There's plenty of kids who hate their parents.
重要的是她有理由恨你
What makes it a big deal is that she should hate you.
打亲血牌什么都改变不了
Playing the biology card doesn't change anything
除了能决定她该住哪
except where she lives.
没有你你女儿过得更好
Your daughter is better off without you.
所以...让她自己好好过吧
So...let her be better off without you.
我要去给她做手术了
I'm gonna do the surgery.
我会解决社会服务部门的遗留问题
I'll take the fallout from Social Services.
豪斯医生
Dr. House!
关心我女儿是我的选择
My daughter's care is my choice.
这也是
And so is this.
按酗酒者治疗她
Treat her for alcoholism.
安妮塔为什么要
Why would Anita
告诉她丈夫我们偷情的事
tell her husband about our affair?
也许是不想再撒谎了
Probably just got sick of lying.
你应该这么想
Look at it this way.
现在你跟她滚床单既不用负责也不用内疚了
Now the sex is both commitment- and guilt-free.
男人都喜欢不用负责的性爱
And men love commitment-free sex.
没错  他们就是这样
Yes, they do.
Oh, yes, they do!
她们最终也会明白的
They're gonna find out eventually.
你怎么能不断重复做着一件事
How do you keep doing the same thing over and over
还保持同样的热情呢
with the same level of enthusiasm?
首先  要做一个正直的考虑别人感受的人
First off, be a decent, empathetic person.
你说过这正是你想要的
This is what you said you wanted,
但她丈夫知道后
but you're actually more upset
你反而更沮丧了
now that her husband knows.
-因为我在伤害他  -以前也是
- 'Cause I'm hurting him. - You always were.
没错  但那时他不知道
Yeah, but he didn't know that.
那意味着他并没有真正意义上的受伤
Which means he wasn't really hurt.
我知道这只是自欺欺人
Yeah, I know it's a rationalization,
但我花了好久才
but it went a long way
稍微感觉...
to making me feel...
和她约会没那么内疚了
A little less guilty about seeing her.
看来你得找个更好的理由
Looks like you're gonna need
来说服自己了
a bigger rationalization.
社会服务部门发来了你母亲的报告
Social Services report came in on your mom.
让我猜猜
Ah, let me guess.
她高分通过了
She passed with flying colors.
她总这样
She always does.
我认为她这次是认真的
I think she might make it this time.
豪斯留下一瓶维科丁
House left a bottle of Vicodin
想看看她是否会偷走
to see if she'd steal it.
她还了回去
She gave it back.
你至少可以让她在这里睡
You could at least let her sleep in the room.
关于喝酒的事她本该相信我
She could have listened to me about my drinking.
我的意思是就算你是对的
I mean, even if you are right about it,
为什么她信你不信我
why take your word over mine?
我是她女儿
I'm her daughter.
因为...
Because it...
她是你母亲
She's your mom.
而且这是第一次她表现得像个母亲
And, for the first time, she's acting like it.
已经有点晚了
It's a little late for that.
晚安
Good night.
早上好
Morning!
我听说你去和那母亲面对面的交流了
I heard you went head-to-head with the mom.
不是为了你想的理由
Not for your reasons.
你是在保护那女孩
You're protecting the girl.
我是在捍卫我的诊断结果
I'm protecting my diagnosis.
你还试探她
And you tested her--
是想知道她是否会重新沾上毒品
see if you could get her back on drugs
并再次离开她女儿
and out of her daughter's life.
那是为了向亚当斯证明妈妈的最爱
That was to show Adams that mommie dearest
从来没有变过
hadn't changed.
我坚决反对这类理想主义
I'm taking a principled stand against idealism.
你的病人还稳定吗
Your patient's stable?
也许亚当斯是对的
Well, maybe Adams was right.
病因与酒精有关
The illness is alcohol-related.
但愿如此
Well, I hope so,
考虑到我们正在以此为根据进行治疗
considering it's what we're treating her for.
你居然为了病人
You--you hope you're wrong
希望自己是错的
for the sake of the patient?
我希望我是对的
I hope that I'm right
但也希望动脉瘤破裂不会杀死她
but the aneurism bursts without killing her.
我就是如此软弱
Call me a softie.
或者她母亲同意我进行尸检
Or the mom agrees to an autopsy
让我证明我是对的也行
so I can prove it.
你的病人们喜欢你因为你富有同情心
Your patients love you because you're empathetic.
我也有双善良的眼睛
I also have kind eyes.
你为什么在这
Why are you here?
但你并不喜欢你所有的病人对吧
But you don't love all your patients?
当然不
Of course not.
我打赌有些也会让你觉得无聊
I'll--I'll bet some of them bore you.
无趣的人也会得癌症
Dull people get cancer too.
你为什么在这
Why are you here?
但你...假装对他们感兴趣
But you...fake an interest in them
因为你必须这样做  是吗
because you needed to, right?
而且如果你装的时间足够长
And if you do it long enough,
那感情就会变成真的了吗
it becomes real?
并非如此
Well, no,
因为兴趣不是假装出来的
because the interest isn't fake.
真的吗
Really?
因为你意识到他们并不是真笨
Because you realize they're not dull.
只是你误解了他们
It was just your misinterpretation of them.
我只是还没找到他们的兴趣点而已
I just haven't found a way to make them interesting yet.
这就是个共同点的问题
It's all about common ground.
你总能找到一样你们都喜欢或讨厌的东西
You found one thing you both like or hate.
吴宇森的电影
John Woo movies,
爱情小说  万人迷
romance novels, kale.
有时候和某人建立联系的最佳方法就是
Sometimes, the best way to connect with someone
不去想他们想要什么而是关注自身
is stop thinking about them and focus on yourself.
这一切是为了什么
Wh--uhh. What is this about?
并非事事都有是目的性的
Not everything has an agenda.
回见
See ya.
我告诉他因为理应如此
I told him because it was the right thing to do.
没错
Right.
这不会对我俩造成任何影响
This doesn't change anything between us.
对我有点影响
It sort of does for me.
你不想再见面了吗
Y-you want to stop seeing each other?
不是
No.
我在想...
I was thinking...
也许你可以告诉你丈夫我们分手了
Maybe you could tell your husband that we did.
然后再背着他
And then go back to sneaking around
和你在一起
behind his back?
没错
Yes.
你为什么想让我这么做
Why would you want to do that?
我不知道  我...
I don't know. I...
现在这样我觉得...
This just feels...
是不对的
Wrong.
我想我该走了
I th--I think I'm gonna go.
上帝啊
Ohh, God.
我们本以为是腌猪肉的问题
We thought it was the salt pork.
但所有人都吃了
But all the menfolk been eatin' it,
只有我们俩病了
and we the only ones that's sick.
你们俩谁是财迷
Which one of you is the cheap bastard?
你们的制服
Your uniforms.
不是羊毛而是涤纶的
They're not wool. They're polyester.
还是便宜的涤纶
Cheap polyester.
在制作过程中会粘上一种叫做
Which gets processed with a heavy metal
锑的重金属
called antimony.
你们一直穿着被重金属污染了
You wear badly processed polyester
一整天的涤纶制服
all day and night for days and nights,
使得你们锑中毒
you get antimony poisoning
导致腹泻
which caused your diarrhea
和你的双手麻木
and your numbness in your hands.
还有你们俩集体呕吐
And your collective vomiting.
涤纶的制服
Polyester uniforms?
我只是在还原历史
I was being authentic.
用涤纶的制服吗
With polyester uniforms?
当时政府每六个月只给士兵21美元
The Confederacy gave men $21 every six months--
-你害我们两个都中毒了  -至少我有原则
- You poisoned us both. - At least I have principles.
因为原则不要钱
Because they don't cost anything.
手足相残
Brother against brother.
这下真实了
Now, that is authentic.
我知道你不想看到我
I know you don't want me here,
但是
but, um...
楼下餐厅有香蕉松饼
They had banana muffins downstairs.
让我想到那次我们去圣彼得斯堡旅行
Reminded me of our St. Pete's trip.
还记得吗
Remember?
那时候我们每天早上一起散步
We used to walk and get some
都去蛋糕房买一些
every morning at that bakery.
好像有这回事
I guess.
那次旅行中你也吸毒了吗
Were you high on that trip?
和你在一起的时候没有
Not when we were together.
我都会等到你睡了以后
I used to wait until you went to bed.
你可以留下
You can stay.
如果你愿意
If you want.
好啊
Okay.
好吃
Mm. It's not bad.
她怎么了
What's happening?
是酒精治疗造成的吗
Is this from the alcohol treatment?
我判断错了
I was wrong.
一定是颅内小动脉瘤破裂
The Berry aneurysm must have just burst.
颞叶没有出血
Temporal lobes are clear.
顶叶也没有
Parietal, clear.
给我一套显微动脉瘤夹
Get me a micro-vascular clip tray
还有闭合器
as well as the occlusion.
检查脑室
Check the ventricles.
脑室也没有
Ventricles are clear too.
动脉瘤一定是发生了渗漏  不是破裂
Aneurysm must have leaked instead of burst.
注射染色剂
Inject the dye.
大脑后动脉没有
Posterior cerebral clear.
椎动脉也没有
Vertebral clear.
威利斯血管环也没有
Circle of Willis also clear.
她没有颅内小动脉瘤
She doesn't have a Berry aneurysm.
血压正在下降  用增压仪
Her BP's dropping. Start her on pressors.
必须在器官衰竭前
We gotta get her BP up
让血压升起来
before her organs start shutting down.
亚当斯  到我这里来
Adams... with me.
增压仪最多只能为我们争取几小时时间
Pressors will only give us a couple hours, max.
什么会导致呼吸问题
What causes breathing issues,
出血和偏瘫
bleeding issues, paralysis,
还有失去意识
loss of consciousness?
我们遗漏了什么
What are we missing?
这些都是负面事件
That's everything bad that's happened.
正面的效果呢
What about the good stuff?
你的意思是我们应该乐观起来吗
You mean like we should be more optimistic?
使用类固醇时病情略有好转
She got a little better when we put her on steroids,
而类固醇能攻击肿瘤细胞
which can attack tumor cells.
她可能患有癌症
Maybe she has cancer.
没有血钙升高  血蛋白也没有升高
No hypercalcemia, no elevated blood proteins.
她和她母亲提到几年前曾经
She and her mom mentioned a trip they took to Florida
去佛罗里达旅行  会不会是登革热
a couple years ago-- what about Dengue fever?
霍乱
Cholera?
奇思妙想  除非登革热和霍乱
Great ideas, if Dengue fever
能够潜伏两年之久
or cholera laid in wait for two years
然后一夕之间...
before suddenly...
你的亲生女儿有在佛罗里达游过泳吗
Did your biological daughter go swimming in Florida?
湖里  池塘  或者湿地
In a lake or a pond or an everglade?
有吧
Uh...Yeah.
我母亲家附近有条水渠
There's a canal near my mother's house.
你知道她的病因了吗
Do you know what's wrong with her?
家庭旅行害死人
Family vacations kill.
跟我来
Come with me.
不想解释两次
Don't want to explain this twice.
你带菌进来了  她需要心室辅助器
You're letting in the flies. And she needs an LVAD.
不  她不需要
No, she doesn't.
你女儿得的是蛔虫病
Your daughter has ascariasis.
是粪便中的寄生虫
It's a disease caused by a parasitic worm
引起的疾病
found in feces.
水渠就是动物的公厕
Animals use the canal as a potty,
凯莉游泳时  寄生虫虫卵
the eggs from the feces ended up in Callie's intestines
进入了她的肠子
when she went swimming...
它们在那里生长
Where they hung out,
悄无声息  没有引起症状
quietly and asymptomatically,
积蓄力量  直到有一天
biding their time till, somewhere along the way,
突然被击散了
they got knocked loose.
可能是排球练习中的一次扑救
Maybe a dive in volleyball practice
也可能是厨房里的一次滑倒
or maybe she slipped on her way into a soup kitchen.
一旦散播开来
But once they hatched,
寄生虫开始破坏她的肺部
the worms got to work on her lungs,
耳和腿部神经
her ear, the nerves in her legs.
这些虫被我们施用的类固醇所刺激
The worms got agitated by the steroids we gave her,
从而向食管移动
which started them on their journey to the esophagus
并且最终到达心脏
and, ultimately, to the heart.
几片甲苯咪唑
A few pills of Mebendazole...
她就没事了
She'll be fine.
她感觉好多了
She's feeling much better.
可以自己走动了
Walking on her own.
跟她母亲相处得好吗
Getting along with her mother?
只要我继续带松饼来
As long as I keep bringing her muffins.
有人带她去做检查了吗
Did someone come take her for a test?
凯莉的想法和你一样
Callie agrees with you...
人是不会变的
That people don't change.
她说她不愿看到
She said when her mom slips again,
妈妈再度堕落
she didn't want to be there.
她宁愿记得妈妈现在的样子
She'd rather remember her like she is now.
聪明姑娘
Smart girl.
你得到了想要的结局
You got the ending you wanted.
因为我的目标只是诊病
'Cause I was only looking to solve the case,
不是挽救他们的人生
not their lives.
我不在乎为我工作的人
Now, I don't care if the people who work for me
是否一团糟
are screwed up.
实际上  我很喜欢这样
In fact, I even encourage it.
可是要普度众生
But absolution?
还是留到业余时间去做
You do that on your own time.
或者别做
Or not at all.
因为你显然也度不了谁
'Cause... Clearly, you suck at it.
给
There.
他是亚伦·罗杰斯
This is Aaron Rodgers.
四分卫评分127哦
Wow, 127 quarterback rating.
知道他叫起来什么样子吗
You know what sound he makes?
好的
Okay. Oy!
这一个
This...
特雷尔·欧文斯
is Terrell Owens.
大家都叫他TO
People call him "T.O."
知道他吼起来什么声音吗
Do you know what sound he makes?
这是马克·桑切斯
This is Mark Sanchez.
知道人们看见他作什么声音吗
Do you know what sound people make about him?
加班吗
Working late?
她今晚跟丈夫过
Husband have her tonight?
以后也是
And every night.
她跟我分了
She broke it off.
对大家都好
It's for the best.
我毕竟不是爱偷情的人
I'm not really an affair guy after all.
老弟  你当然是
Sure you are, buddy.
只不过现在不再是偷了  你没了兴致
You just lost interest once it stopped being an affair.
所以分了你反而安心
That's why you're relieved.
别担心  这里不是终点
But don't worry-- it's not gonna end here.
总有他处能让你肾上腺素得到修复
You'll just have to get your adrenaline fix somewhere else.
等到偷情也激不起你的肾上腺素
When that doesn't do it anymore,
你就会
then you'll just...
找到其它稀奇古怪的途径
escalate things somehow.
至少我听说是这样的
At least, that's what I've been told.
豪斯  我和你不一样
I'm not like you, House.
当然  你又不瘸
True... no limp.